WASHINGTON;D,C
华盛顿特区
We are sick with their plague.
他们的瘟疫病倒了我们
They will infect us all.
他们会传染给我们
We must exterminate.Start a new day...
我们必须消灭一切 开始新生活...
I'm sorry.
对不起
You're Dr.Reid.
你是Reid博士
I'm sorry.Do I know you?
对不起 我认识你吗?
I just know what you do.
我知道你而已
Ok.
好吧
I saw you in georgetown a few weeks ago.
几周前我在Georgetown大学见过你
You gave a lecture on sexual sadism and
你在做关于性虐待的演讲
how you helped catch the mill creek killer in st.Louis.
以及你如何在St.Louis 帮忙捕获Mill Creek杀手的事迹
I-I'm not much of a,uh-- a public speaker.
我不太会...公众演讲
I don't know.I thought you seemed cool.
我不知道 我觉得你挺酷的
You look kind of young to go to georgetown.
你上Georgetown大学 还太年轻了一点吧
Um,I'm a junior at northwest high school.
我在西北高中读三年级
And you just go to lectures on anger excitation for fun?
所以你是因为好玩 而去听关于刺激愤怒的讲座?
I don't have a lot of friends.
我没什么朋友
So you're interested in profiling?
你对人物分析有兴趣?
Yeah.I mean,
是的
I read a lot,you know,true crime,
我看过很多真实案例
like graphic novels,mostly.
大多数像是图解小说
They're all about whether there's really such a thing as evil,
都是关于是否有恶魔存在
like nature versus nurture,all that,
比如 本性对抗教养...
so i figured it'd be smart to hear it from an expert,you know?
我想听听专家的看法 应该有帮助
So you said a lot of 'em kill prostitutes?
你说很多人会杀妓女?
It's the number one serial killer target,actually.
事实上 这是连环杀手的首要目标
Well,is that for sex or because they think they're dirty and they need to be punished?
是因为性吗? 还是觉得她们肮脏因而需要惩治?
Were you waiting here for me?
你是特意在这等我吗?
What would it mean if somebody were stabbing them and cutting off their hair?
如果有人刺死她们 并剪掉她们头发 那意味着什么?
I've never,uh-- I've never heard of a case like that.
我...从未听过这样的案例
Do you wanna go to the bau with me,
你要不和我回BAU
maybe talk to some of my other team members?
和我的组员谈一谈?
I actually have to go to school.
我得上课去了
Give me your--your name and your number,and I'll call you and
告诉我名字和电话 我打给你...
F.B.I..Behavioral Analysis Unit QUANTICO,VIRGINIA
FBI 行为分析小组 维吉尼亚州 Quantico市
hey,spence.
嘿 Spence
Jj,who's your contact at the D.C. Police?
JJ 你在华盛顿警方的联系人是谁?
Uh,victor barnes.Why?You need me to call him?
Victor Barnes 你要我打电话给他?
Hi.Detective barnes,please.
麻烦我找Barnes探长
What's wrong?
怎么了?
Need to get that to everyone as soon as possible.
得尽快把这个给所有人看
Uh,hi.Detective barnes,this is special agent dr.Spencer reid at the behavioral analysis unit at quantico.
Barnes探长 我是行为分析组 特别探员Spencer Reid博士
Have you had any recent murders involving prostitutes,
你们最近有涉及妓女的谋杀案吗?
maybe just jane does?
也许只是无名女尸?
They would have been stabbed to death,and their hair would've been cut off by the killer.
她们是被刺死的 并且头发被剪掉
When was the most recent victim?
最近一个受害者是什么时候?
I'll explain when I see you.I'll meet you in a half-hour.
见面再解释 半小时后见
What's going on?
发生什么了?
D.C. May have a serial killer.
华盛顿里也许有个连环杀手
I think I just let him get away.
我刚放他跑了
T.S.Eliot wrote,
T.S. Eliot写道
"between the idea and the reality,"
"在理想与现实之间
between the motion and the act,
动机与行为之间
falls the shadow.
总有阴影徘徊"
" We found her 4 days ago in an aly off "k" street.
四天前在K大街的小巷发现她的
Still no I.D.
目前还没查出身份
Hey.Just got your message.
刚收到你消息
Aaron hotchner,vic barnes.
这位是Aaron Hotchner
Hi.What have we got?
- 你好 - 有什么发现?
This is the second victim.
这是第二个受害者
The first one was killed 3 months ago,
第一个是在三个月前被杀害
both in the early morning.
都是在大清早
Both had their hair chopped?
头发都被剪掉?
Uniform didn't make the connection,because he was fixated on this.
统一并不构成联系 因为他的注意力都集中在这里
The first victim didn't have anything carved on her?
第一个受害者身上没有刻东西?
Just a routine jane doe.
只是个寻常无名女尸
Take a look.
看
A lot are shallow.They're hesitation marks.
大多都很浅 刻得非常犹豫
He's not certain he wants to be killing.
他不确定是否要杀人
Makes you think the message he carved is sincere.
会让你觉得他刻下的信息很真诚
He's asking the police to help him stop.
他在祈求警方阻止他
Fits with your kid seeking you out.
和来找你的那个小伙子很符合
Part of him wants to get caught.
他有点想被抓住
I let him go.I'm sorry.
我放他走了 对不起
We'll find him.
我们会找到他
If both murders took place in the morning,how come there were no witnesses?
如果两起案件都发生在早晨 为什么没有目击者?
The motels and alleys around the capitol are notorious.
首都周围的汽车旅馆和小巷都臭名昭著
People go out of their way not to look.
为了不要看 人们还会绕路
At night,no one can see down there.
晚上 没人能看那里
During the day,
白天
you just duck behind the dumpster or into a doorway.
就躲在垃圾桶后或是门廊内
Business is pretty heavy here in the mornings?
早上生意很好吗?
How do I know you're not just lookin' to crack down on us?
我怎么知道你不是来扫黄的?
Because I'm telling you.
因为我要告诉你
We're here trying to protect you.
我们是来保护你
A lot of johns from the hill stop by on their way to work.
很多嫖客都会在上班途中经过这里
We always say the same politicians yellin' about cleanin' up the hill,
我们一直说那些政客 呼吁着要扫清小山
the ones droppin' 50 bucks with us before they make the speech.
而其实是在演讲前 丢给我们50美元
It's true,and the more important they think they are,
这是真的 他们越觉得自己重要
the quicker they accidentally finish up with us.
就越快和我们划清界限
It's weird like that.
奇怪的很
No,that's pretty much universal.
不 这再正常不过
You recognize him at all?
你认得他吗?
I don't know his name or nothin'.
我不知道他叫什么
He hangs around,tries to pretend like he's not watching us.
他四处转悠 假装没在看我们
He's just a horny kid,you know.
只是个色小孩罢了
You didn't see him talking to any of the other girls out here?
你有看过他和这里其他人说过话吗?
I just figured he's the kind gets his little bit of danger
我只是觉得 他是那种不敢惹麻烦
and goes home and takes business into his own hands.
回家用手解决问题的人
Is he the one who did this?
是这个人杀的?
We don't know,but someone did,
不知道 但总有人是凶手
so you need to be careful.
你们得小心
We stick to the daylight and only work the high-end blocks.
我们都是白天上班 而且只在高端街道
How old are you?
你多大了?
21.
21岁
19.
19岁
Just watch out for each other,ok?
互相照顾 小心点
Oh,agent hotchner,karen steyer.
Hotchner探员 我是Karen Steyer
Congresswoman,how do you do?
议员女士 你好
I'm fine,thank you.They said it was fine to wait in here.
谢谢 他们让我在这里等
Of course.What can I do for you?
有什么能帮忙的?
Well,I have talked to my people,
我跟我的人谈过了
and I understand that we have a potential serial killer targeting prostitutes in D.C.
我知道在华盛顿潜在着 一个以妓女为目标的连环杀手
That was awfully fast.
消息传得还真快
I have awfully good people.
我的人都很强
Sounds like it.
听出来了
I'd like you to promise me that if your team stays on the case,
我要你向我保证 如果你们小组继续负责这个案子
uh,you won't publicize the murders.
就不要将谋杀案公布于众
I'm afraid I can't make that promise.
我恐怖不能保证
With all due respect,you will notice that I said,
恕我直言   你应该注意到我说的
"if you stay on the case.
"如果你们还负责这个案子"
" I really don't like doing this,honestly
老实说 我真的不想这么做
but as you know,the bau cannot join an investigation
你也清楚  你们BAU小组是不能插手调查
unless they are invited by the local enforcement agency.
如果没有当地执法部门的申请
What's this about?
你到底想说什么？
6 months ago,I introduced a major initiative declaring crime in D.C.An epidemic.
六个月前 我提出一个主要草案 报道华盛顿的犯罪
I'm familiar with the bill.
我很熟悉这个法案
Makes additional federal funds available.
增加了额外的联邦基金
You target lifestyle crimes like prostitution and drug use,
你把目标指向生活方式的罪犯 像是妓女和吸毒者
and hopefully the overall crime rate drops.
正如希望 整体犯罪率降低了
Worked in new york.
在纽约很适用
It worked in L.A.It's worked here.
在洛杉矶也是 这里也是
And in 4 days,I'm set to stand at the base of the capitol
四天后 我将要站在首都之基
and announce that petty crime in D.C.
宣布华盛顿的轻微犯罪率下降43%
Is down 43% and violent crime is down 37%.
暴力犯罪率下降37%
The last thing I need is the press announcing that we have a serial killer murdering prostitutes.
我最不想看到的就是媒体报道 有个谋杀妓女的连环杀手
I understand that.
我明白
But by not alerting the media,
但如果不公之于众
we're putting women at risk.
那些女人就身处险境
I'm not asking you to back down.
我不是要你罢手
Work your case.
继续查你的案子
Catch your killer.
抓你的凶手
Just do it quietly.
只要给我安静点
And if I don't?
如果我不答应呢?
I guarantee you won't work it at all.
我保证 你就不用再继续做下去了
Oh,a little unsolicited advice.
给你点建议
You're driven.You're bright.
你很有冲劲而且聪明
You're exactly the kind of person who could run the bureau someday.
绝对是管理FBI的人才
You might as well accept now
你倒不如现在就接受
that leading the fbi has as much to do with politics
领导FBI不仅需要跟政治打交道的
as it does with law enforcement.Good day.
还得和执法部门打交道   祝你好运
This is impossible.
这不可能
Says you.
你说呢
There's nothing in the juvenile offender records.
青少年犯罪记录里什么都没有
So you think like a high school kid.
你得像个高中生一样的思考
I was 12,and I hadn't been through puberty when I was in high school.
我当时12岁 我上高中时还没度过青春期呢
Ok,reset.
好吧 重新开始
I think like a high school student.
我来想象成高中生
You think like a profiler.
而你是行为分析师
He said he was a junior,right?
他说他高三学生  对吗?
Mm-hmm.
恩
The first rule of the teen years,
青少年的第一法则
when talking to an authority figure,always lie and say you're older.
在跟政府人士说话时 要把自己的年龄说大些
He's probably a sophomore.
他可能只是高二
Ok.
好吧
His coat was lamb's wool,
他的外衣是羊毛
but it didn't look vintage.
但看起来不过时
It   fit like it had been tailored for him.
好像是度身定做似的 非常合适
That means money.
那意味着金钱
In D.C.,Money would mean private school.
在华盛顿 金钱就代表私立学校
Look at you go.
说得好
-Even a lie has to be within the depth of your own experience,right? -Fair enough,fair enough.
- 即使撒谎 也要在个人经历范围内吧 - 没错 没错
Uh   I'm a junior at northwest high school.
我在西北高中读三年级
Pull up the district that serves northwest high.
找到西北高中的地区范围
Are there any private schools within those boundaries?
附近有私立学校吗?
Uh,3.
恩 3个
Do any of them offer elective courses at georgetown?
有提供在Georgetown大学的选修课吗?
One.The morton school.
一个 Morton学校
-Pull up the junior class. -Ah!
- 调出三年级的学生 - 啊!
Uh,sophomore class.
二年级
Ah,if I do say so myself.
我自己都会这么说的
Wait,wait.Stop.
等等 停
Nathan harris.
Nathan Harris
We got him.
我们找到他了
The blade slices the whore's neck.
刀刃切断了妓女的脖颈
I'll be right there.
我来开门
Ooh ooh,ooh ooh ooh
请问有什么事？
I'm jason gideon with the fbi. Dr. Reid.Agent morgan.
我是FBI的Jason Giden 这是Reid博士和Morgan探员
The whore falls.
妓女倒下了
We're looking for your son nathan.
我们要找你的儿子Nathan
Why?
为什么?
Bloody.Dead.
血淋的 死去了
We just wanna ask him some questions.
我们想问他几个问题
Well,not until you explain what's going on.
除非告诉我发生了什么事
Uh,your son came to talk to me this morning about a murder case.
你的孩子今天早上跑来告诉我一桩凶杀案
Why would nathan know anything about a murder?
Nathan怎么会知道凶杀的事?
No,mom,it's true.
不 妈妈 是真的
I--I did talk to him.
我--我的确跟他谈过
I'm just 19 do you mind if I speak to him alone?****************不确定
你不介意我单独跟他谈谈吧?
-We'll stay out here,ma'am. -O-ok.
- 我们在外面等 夫人 - 好的
I knew if you were really good,you'd find me.
我知道如果你们很出色就能找到我
Is that why you were waiting for me?
所以你在等我们?
You--you wanted to get caught?
你--你想被抓起来?
What do you mean,"get caught"?
什么叫"被抓起来"?
Oh-- hey.
哦--嘿!
Stay right there and keep your hands where I can see them.
就站在那里 把手放在我能看得到的地方
It's just the text for a graphic novel.
这只是一本精彩小说里面的文字
About killing prostitutes?
关于杀害妓女的?
Yeah,jack the ripper.It's a famous case.
是的 开膛手杰克 很有名的案子
This isn't a game,kid.
这可不是游戏 孩子
I know.
我知道
You knew specific details about a murder that hasn't been publicized.
你知道一桩凶杀案的细节 可那案子还没有公开
But I didn't kill her.
但我没有杀她
I just   I really wanted to.
我只是很想那么做
Nathan,if you didn't do it,how'd you know the details of the murder?
Nathan 要是你没做过 你怎么知道得那么详细?
'Cause I saw the body.
因为我看到了尸体
It was early.It was before school.
那时还很早 没到上学时间
She--she was dressed in red.
她--她穿着红色的衣服
She'd been stabbed a lot,and her hair was all chopped off.
她被刺了好多刀 她的头发也被剃掉了
Where was that?
在哪?
In an alley off of "k" street.
在K街一条小巷里
They take men down there for sex.I see 'em do it all the time.
她们带男人去那里办事 我总是看到他们那样
What were you doing down there?
你去那里做什么?
I don't know.I just sort of
我也不清楚 我只是…
end up there sometimes,you know?
总走到那里 你知道吗?
I--I stay out all night,and I just come back in the morning,
我整晚都呆在外面 早上才回来
and if my mom's at work,I don't even bother coming home.
要是我妈妈在工作 就更不用回家了
Thinking dark thoughts is a far cry from being a danger.
有些阴暗的想法离真正的危险还远着呢
I know that.
我知道
I don't think anyone's personal demons would hold up to scrutiny.
我认为个人内心世界的魔鬼不该拿出来详细审查
Mine wouldn'T.Would yours?
我的不会 你会吗?
No.
不会
He's a good boy.
他是个好孩子
He's exceptionally bright.
非常聪明
He just lives in his head more than other kids.
只是比起别的孩子 他更愿意活在内心世界里
So it's just the two of you?
那么只有你们俩?
His father died when he was 9.
他父亲在他9岁的时候去世了
How'd he handle that?
他怎么对待这事的?
Well,emotionally it was grueling,
感情上是一个重创
but we got through it together.
但我们一起扛过来了
-And you're close. -Hmm.
- 你们很亲密 - 恩
I'd say very.
我得说非常亲密
Don't go misinterpreting that.
但别曲解
You teach at G.W.Medical school,you're also on call at the hospital?
你在乔治华盛顿医学样教书 同时也在医院任职?
2 weeks a month.
每个月两周
So nathan must have a lot of freedom.
那么Nathan一定很自由了
I treat him like a man,because he's always handled his responsibility.
我象大人那样对待他 因为他总是很有责任感
Why didn't you call the police?
为什么不叫警察
I don't know.
我不知道
Nathan,the prostitutes I talked to say you watch them.
Nathan 跟我谈过的妓女说你看着她们
I'd never touch them.
我从没摸过她们
You fantasize about having sex with them?
你幻想和她们做爱?
No,I told you,I think about killing them.
不 我跟你说了我想杀了她们
Look,after the lecture,
看 那次演讲后
I saw you at the metro stop a few times,
我在地铁站看到过你几回
and I thought maybe you could help me.
我想你能帮助我
How?
怎么帮?
I don't know.I saw that body,
我不知道 我看到那具尸体
and I felt excited,and that really scared me.
我觉得兴奋 这感觉让我害怕
Is it possible that you actually killed those prostitutes,
那可能因为你真的杀了她们
but you just don't want to admit it to yourself?
但你并不想对自己承认?
No.
不
Then why'd you run away from me?
那你为什么要逃跑?
'Cause I don't know,but I thought you'd say I was crazy and there was no way to stop it.
因为我不知道 但我觉得你会说我疯了 而且没办法停止
-Thank you. -Sure.
- 谢谢 - 好的
Ma'am,we'd like to let the juvenile authorities hold him overnight so we can do a psychological evaluation.
夫人 我们想让他呆在少管所过夜 这样我们可以做一个精神方面的评估
I can't believe this is real.
真不敢相信
Well,right now it's just an evaluation.
目前只是个评估
I'd encourage nathan to have a lawyer present.
我建议Nathan找个律师在场
I don't know what he's going through,
我不知道他正经历着什么
but the nathan I know is a sweet boy.
但据我所知Nathan是个好孩子
I believe you.
我相信你
Do we have your permission?
我们能得到你的允许吗?
I'll show you where to sign the paperwork.
我会告诉你在哪里签字
The juvenile authorities are waiting for nathan harris.
少管所在等Nathan Harris
He's in interrogation.
他在审讯中
Is he our unsub?
他是我们的不明人物吗?
I don't know.
我不知道
He says he didn't do it.
他说他没做过
He actually seems sincere.
他看起来很真诚
But he's a smart kid,
但他是个聪明的孩子
and part of the sexual-sadist profile is the ability to mimic honesty and sincerity.
而性虐待狂的一个特征就是有模仿正直真诚的能力
The police are here for you.
警察来接你了
Dr. Reid.
Reid博士
Yeah?
什么事?
I know I,um,don't deserve any favors,
我知道不该得到任何优待
but whatever my psych eval says,you promise you'll tell me the truth?
但不管我的精神评估是什么样的 你保证告诉我真相好吗?
Um,my mom says a promise doesn't count unless you say it out loud.
妈妈说大声说出来的保证才算数
I promise.
我保证
Ok.Thank you.
好的 多谢
You know,he might have killed 2 women.
他可能杀了两个女人
It's not your job to hold his hand through this.
在这件事上拉他一把可不是你的工作
It's like with my mom.
这就跟我妈妈一样
I used to think that if I could just understand
我过去想过 要是我能完全了解
absolutely everything there is to know about schizophrenia,
精神分裂症的种种情况
then I'd somehow be able to fix it.
那么我就可能治好它
You can'T.I'm sorry.
你不能 很遗憾
Guys.I need everybody in the conference room.
两位 我想让大家到会议室集合
If nathan harris isn't our unsub,we need a working profile.
如果Nathan Harris不是我们的不明人物 我们得再做出一个犯罪描述
D.C.Police sent us these photos of the first victim.
特区警方把第一个受害人的照片送来了
This was the unsub's first kill.
这是不明人物的第一次杀戮
He held his urges in check for 3 months,
他克制着自己的欲望达三个月
and when he couldn't control them any more,he sent this message to the cops.
当他无法再控制的时候 他给警察发出了讯息
We know the "help" and the hesitation marks mean he was ambivalent about the kill.
我们知道"求救"和犹豫的标志 意味着他对杀人非常矛盾
What we don't know is why he chopped the hair.
我们不知道的是为什么要削掉头发
He didn't take it with him.
他没有带走头发
We know it's not a trophy.
所以那不是战利品
It's probably a way to minimize some of their power,robs them of their femininity.
也许仅仅是为了减少她们的能量 夺去她们女性的特征
That fits with him killing during the early morning.
这也与在清晨杀人吻合
It's the time when prostitutes have the least power sexually,
正是妓女们最不具性感的时候
as opposed to at night,when he might see them as being on the prowl.
与夜晚 他看到他们游荡的时候相反
Hey,I know we're just spitballing this here,
我知道我们正在说这个
but this profile points to nathan harris.
但犯罪描述指向的是Nathan Harris
I don't wanna talk about nathan harris.
我不想谈Nathan Harris
Hotch,she is right.
Hotch 她是对的
He reached out for help.
他来请求帮助
This is an adolescent kid.
这是个处在青春期的孩子
He's probably intimidated sexually.
他也许被性困扰
I don't care how many times he says he didn't do it.
我不在乎他说了多少遍他没做
He knew about the last victim,and he admitted to getting off on seeing her dead.
他知道最后一个受害人 他承认看她死掉很兴奋
We've got nathan harris.
我们已经抓住Nathan Harris了
It doesn't do us any good to talk about him now.
再谈他也无济于事
I just wanna make sure that if it's not him,
我只想搞清楚如果不是他会怎么样
we stay on top of thing before it takes on a life of its own.
我们得在无法控制之前搞清楚
All right,all right,all right.
好啦 好啦 好啦
We know our unsub is a sexual sadist.
我们知道 不明人物是个性虐待狂
The symbolism of stabbing them probably means he's impotent.
用刀刺可能表示他性无能
The only way he can get off is by killing.
只有杀人才能让他兴奋起来
Considering that cutting their hair and killing during the
考虑到削去她们的头发
early morning both stem from feeling powerless,
并且在清晨杀人 都是由于感觉无能
there's a chance his pathology's more than sexual.
所有也有可能并不是性而是病
What do you mean?
什么意思?
This is D.C.Power's the most important commodity.
这里是特区 权力是最重要的日用品
Maybe this guy feels impotent in his professional life as well.
也可能是这家伙觉得在职业生涯中无能
But why these particular women?
为什么选这类特殊的女人?
Simplest answer is that he has access.
最简单的答案是他有权接近
Well,northwest D.C.Has 3 major hubs of prostitution--
在特区西北部有三个主要的妓女集中地
near florida avenue;
接近佛罗里达大街
off logan circle;
洛根商圈
and mcpherson square,where the victims were found.
以及麦克弗森广场 就是发现受害人的地方
Probably works in or around capitol hill.
也许就在国会山里或附近工作
Well,I'll go back out on the street in the morning
我会早上再回到街上
and see if any of these women know someone who fits that description.
看看是否有人知道与描述相吻合的人
Good.
好的
It's late.Let's go home.
很晚了 回家吧
Um,shouldn't we get word out to the papers?
我们要不要向媒体说什么?
Not yet.
还不行
Well,it's not too late to make the morning edition.
现在做早版还不晚
I said no.
我说了不要
Hey!
嗨!
You seen little holly?
你见过小Holly吗?
新MM说，*********************************
这次刻的是“失败”
she was only 19
她才16岁
Hotch说,**********************************
他在因为警方没能制止住他的冲动而生气
Reid说**************************************
也肯定不会在进行更多的凶杀之前冷静下来
Morgan************************
说明我们还会见到更多的尸体
Hotch说,**********************************
与此同时 国会议员Steyer将会在2天前 在国会大厦前宣布华盛顿特区为无犯罪区
新MM说***********************
那天她到底想要你做什么?
Morgan************************
我猜Nathan Harris不是我们要找的不明人物
Reid说**************************************
不要 我们还没弄清楚他到底是怎么回事
Reid说****************************no
而这个必须弄明白
Does he have to be here?
他一定要在这儿吗?
It's for your own protection.
这是为了保护你
He's here to make sure we're not talking about the case,just about you.
他在这里是为了确保我们没有谈案子 只谈你
So I don't wet the bed or start fires.
我没有玩火 或者尿床
Heh.
呵呵
I see you've read dr.Harris' warning signs of psychopathy.
看得出你读过Harris医生的精神变态的警告信号
Yeah.Is that wrong?
是的 有什么不对吗?
No,it's healthy.
不 这很健康
You're intellectually curious.
你很有求知欲
You wanna understand how you're feeling.
你想了解你是怎么感觉的
So you don't wet the bed or start fires.
所以你不尿床也不玩火
Tell me what worries you.
告诉我什么困扰你
I've just been,um
我只是 恩
thinking about stuff.
不停地思考
About hurting women?
怎么杀女人?
Yeah.
是的
Have you ever hurt anyone?
你伤害过什么人吗?
I killed a bird once.
我杀过一只鸟
I know that's on the list.It's one of the signs.
我知道这也是一种信号
Why'd you kill the bird?
你为什么要杀鸟?
'Cause I was sad.
因为我感觉伤心
How'd you feel afterwards?
事后感觉如何?
Better.
好些了
Why?
为什么?
I don't know,'cause
我不知道 因为
it was dead,and I was still alive.
它死了而我还活着
Is that why you wanna hurt women,to feel better?
你也是为了想感觉好些才想伤害女人?
I don't know.
我不知道
Have you ever seen a woman naked?
你见过体的女人吗?
Don't worry about him.
别管他
No offense.
无意冒犯
None taken.
没事
Um   a few years ago.
呃 几年前
My mom's med school,her students get cadavers.
在我妈妈的医学校里 她的学生拿到尸体
So how'd that make you feel?
那让你如何感觉?
Good.
很好
Excited.
兴奋
And sick.
以及恶心
Perfectly natural,boy to feel excited,he sees a naked body,even a cadaver.
非常自然的 看到一具体时男孩会感到兴奋 即使是尸体
Yeah,but now that's the only part that I think about.
是的 但那成了我唯一想的那部分
Which part?
哪部分?
Them being dead.
她们已经死了
So when you watch the prostitutes,you don't imagine having sex with them?
那么当你看到那些妓女 不会想象和她们做爱吗?
No,I think about cutting them.
不 我想的是切割她们
Why?
为什么?
I don't know,maybe to look inside.
不知道 也许是想看到里面
Or sometimes I think about
或者有时候 我想
feeling their blood in my hands and feeling it flow through my fingers.
感觉她们的血沾满我的手 感觉鲜血从我的手指间流走
Does that ever make you climax,
那让你有高潮吗?
just by thinking of that?
只是想着
I know I'm crazy.
我知道我疯了
Did I say that?
我这么说过吗?
No,but
没有 但是
what do you call pictures in your head that you can't make go away?
你管那些在脑海里无法抹去的图象叫做什么?
Can I talk to you?
我能跟你谈一下吗?
Stay here.I'll be right back.
呆在这 我就回来
It's my opinion that nathan should be hospitalized.
我认为是Nathan应该住院治疗
What?
什么?
I think he needs full-time medical attention.
我觉得他需要24小时医疗看护
I'm a doctor.
我是医生
He's having homicidal fantasies that are directly linked to his sexual impulses and release.
他有杀人幻想 这直接与他的性冲动和释放有关
Well, he came to your agent.
他去找了你的探员
That shows that he's concerned.
这说明他很在意自己的情况
In his heart, he doesn't want to hurt anyone.
他内心并不希望伤害别人
Positive sign, but intelligence and awareness don't always allow us to control our urges.
积极的信号 但理智和清醒 并不总能让我们控制自己的欲望
Admitting the problem doesn't mean you can manage it.
承认问题并不等于你能处理它
If I put him in a hospital, I'd be telling him that he's a monster.
如果送他进医院 我就等于告诉他 他是个魔鬼
No, no, no, no, no.
不....
He's just-- right now he's sick, and he needs help.
他只是--现在他病了 他需要帮助
No.
不
If an alcoholic cannot control his impulses, ma'am, he drinks.
是否酒鬼不能控制自己的冲动 --夫人 他喝酒
You need to consider what happens with someone fighting psychotic urges.
你得考虑到 一个与精神欲念搏斗的人会怎么样
I'm not naive.
我可不天真
I'm not gonna turn a blind eye, but I have to protect my son.
我不是故意视而不见 但我要保护我的孩子
He needs to be with professionals.
他需要专业人士来照顾
I have access to the best in washington.
我有办法请到华盛顿最好的人
I'll make sure that he sees someone every single day, but I am not gonna lock him away.
我会确保他每天都接受治疗 但我不想把他关起来
Have a seat.
请坐
I don't appreciate being questioned in front of other agents.
我不想在其他探员面前被质疑
It was not my intention.
这不是我的意图
I'm sorry.
对不起
What were you talking to congresswoman steyer about the other day?
那天你和国会议员Steyer在谈什么?
She stopped by to say hello.
她只是停下来打个招呼
She worked with my mother, so I've known her since I was a kid.
她和我妈妈一起工作 所以我从小就认识她
Did you tip her off about this case?
你向她透露过这个案子吗?
No.
没有
This team can't function if I don't trust the people on it.
如果我不能信任组里的人 这个组就无法行使职责
Sir, if I touched a nerve out there today, I'm sorry, but I don't deserve this.
长官 要是我今天有什么冒犯 很对不起 但也不能这样对待我
You mysteriously showed up at the bau after one of my team members was involved in a questionable shooting.
当我的一个组员遭到可疑枪击的时候 你神秘的出现在BAU
Right.
是的
You've done good work.
你的工作干的很不错
I'm not questioning that.
我不是质疑那个
But I will not put up with a political agenda.
但我不能容忍政治
My mother's a career politician.
我妈妈的职业就是政治家
You worked with her.
你和她一起工作
Did you like her?
你喜欢她吗?
She's an impressive women.
她是位令人印象深刻的女士
Well, I think politics makes people distrustful.
我觉得政治让人互不信任
I think it makes them hate themselves.
我觉得它让人们互相憎恨
I think it tears families apart and damages people.
我觉得它破坏家庭 伤害人们
So if there's nothing else,
那么要是没别的事
I would like to get back out on the street and find out who's killing these women.
我想回到街上找出谁杀了那些女人
Sir.
长官
Have you reached a conclusion about nathan harris yet?
对于Nathan Harris你们有什么结论了吗?
Profiles and evaluations are an inexact science.
犯罪描述和评估不是精确的科学
But your professional opinion?
但以你的专业观点来看呢?
Not a question of whether he ends up killing someone.
毫无疑问他最后会发展成为杀人犯
It's when.
问题在于什么时候
Nathan.
Nathan
Nathan, honey.
Nathan 亲爱的
Oh, my god.
天哪
He's gotta be out here, right?
他肯定应该在这附近 不是吗?
Where else would he be?
他还能去哪儿?
I still can't believe his mother's not out here searching for him.
我真不敢相信他妈妈没有出去找他
I told her it'd be better if she waited for him at home.
我跟她说了最好在家等他
Reid, you know this is not your responsibility.
Reid 这不是你的责任
It is.
是我的
I can't explaiN.
我没法解释
Well, try me.
解释给我听吧
He knows I understand him.
他知道我了解他
Of course you do.
你当然了解
You're a profiler.
你是犯罪描述专家
It's more than that.
还不止
How?
怎么?
I know what it's like to be afraid of your own mind.
我知道害怕自己的想法是怎么样的
What's up with hotch today?
Hotch今天怎么了?
I don't know.
不知道
Maybe he tied that knot in his tie a little too tight again.
也许又是领带系得太紧了
Yeah.
请说?
Ok.
好的
We're on our way.
我们在路上了
They just found a body.
他们发现了一具尸体
I'd say he's getting bolder.
我得说他越来越大胆了
If it's the same unsub.
如果是同一个不明人物
Think it could've been nathan?
有可能是Nathan吗?
This kill was fast and messy.
这次杀人又快又乱
There's no cut hair, no message carved.
没有削头发 没有刻上消息
Not to mention killing at night.
更不用说在夜里杀人
None of it's our unsub's signature.
没有一样是我们那个不明人物的特征
Excuse me, agent.
对不起 探员
They found the boy you're looking for.
他们找到那个男孩了
Says he's beenere 4 hours.
听说他在这呆了4个小时
Got a lot of people worried.
好多人在担心你
Sorry.
对不起
Told that policeman that you've been here 4 hours?
你告诉警察你在这里呆了4个小时?
I snuck out, and I started walking, like I couldn't control it,
我偷偷跑出来 然后一直走 我没法控制自己
so I figured I'd come here and try and fight it.
所以我想我到这来可以战胜它
Has anybody seen you here?
有人看到你吗?
Doesn't matter, anyway.
无所谓了
It does matter, nathan.
有所谓的 Nathan
A woman was stabbed tonight, and nobody saw you.
今晚有个女人被刺死了 可没人见过你
I'm gonna have to bring you in as a suspect.
我不得不把你当成嫌疑犯
You gonna cuff me?
你要铐上我?
Let's go.
走吧
Do you wanna know what I've been doing all night?
你想知道我整晚都在做什么吗?
Hmm?
恩?
Just been sitting here, thinking
坐在这想呀想呀
the only way for me to save people's lives in the future is to kill myself.
唯一让我不杀人的方法 就是先杀了我自己
So nathan's in custody?
Nathan被拘留了?
They're holding him downtown.
他们在市区抓到他
You really think he killed that last woman?
你们真以为他杀了那个女人?
It's possible.
有可能
But nathan's evolving.
但是Nathan在进步
This last kill, it feels like a devolution.
最后一起杀人 却象是退步
It was sloppy and angry.
潦草又狂暴
Nathan's smart and directed.
Nathan是机智和有控制的
He's used to achieving.
他习惯于达成目标
If he decides to kill, it'll be clinical and efficient.
如果他决定杀人 就会冷静而有效
So where does that leave us?
那么我们能得到什么?
Back to the profile.
回到犯罪描述上来
First victim, he gets a taste for killing.
第一人受害人 让他体会了杀戮的味道
Second, he asks the police to help stop him.
第二个 他请求警察阻止他
By the third, he feels like they've failed him.
到了第三个 他感觉他们击败了他
He's already devolving.
他已经退步了
The fourth, no ritual, no message, just a brutal murder.
第四个 没有仪式 没有消息 只是残忍的凶杀
It's true that he's devolving, but this last victim definitely had a message.
他的确是退步了 但最后一个受害者无疑传达了一个消息
You don't dump a body across from the capitol building by accident.
把尸体丢在国会大厦可不是偶然之举
Especially not when a congresswoman is about to proclaim success against the crime epidemic.
特别是当一个国会女议员 就要宣布对犯罪流行的胜利时
Exactly.
正是如此
Guys, that press conference wasn't announced yet.
各位 新闻发布会并没有宣布
Only someone with inside information would know that.
只是内线才会知道
We profiled the unsub felt limited in his job.
对于这个不明人物 我们的描述是他在工作上受到限制
What's more powerless than being a bit player on the washington stage?
谁会比政治舞台上的演员们更无权无势?
You know, if he felt like he did his part to clear the prostitutes off the street, but was never heard,
如果他觉得他完成了他的工作 把妓女从街头清除出去 却无人知晓
he might have felt so personally betrayed that he literally had to carve his frustration out on those women.
被背叛的亲身感觉 会让他真的在那些女人身上刻下他的沮丧
So the profile was right.
那么描述是正确的
We were just wrong about who the message was for.
我们错在这些信息是送给谁的
We need to get a list of anyone who advocated on behalf of that bill.
我们要列出一张这个提案的提倡者的清单
Prentiss, when you went back to talto the prostitutes, did a profile ring a bell with any of them?
Prentiss 你回去和这些妓女谈时 有没有一个与描述吻合的?
A few of them described what sounded like the same man, but when I showed them mug shots, I came up empty.
有几个形容的象是同一个人 但给他们看嫌疑犯照片的时候 却没有相配的
Let's go bk to them.We're gonna need their help.
我们再回去找他们 我们需要他们的帮助
What are you thinking about, hotch?
你在想什么 Hotch?
I need to get a message to congresswoman steyer.
我得拿到一个给国会议会Steyer的消息
How quickly can we put together a press conference?
我们多快能举办一个新闻发布会?
How fast do you need it?
你想多快?
May I have your attention, please?
请大家注意
A day from now, there will be an announcement across the street on the steps of the capitol
一天后 将在街对面的国会大厦台阶上发布一项公告
that crime is down significantly in washington.
华盛顿的犯罪率有了可观的下降
This is a fact.
这是事实
It is also a fact however, that there's a serial killer who's been targeting the prostitutes who work in this area.
另一个事实是 连环杀手选择在这个区域工作的妓女为目标
In fact, the last victim was fod not a hundred yards from where we're standing.
事实上 最后一名受害人 就是在离我们所站的地方不到100码的地方发现的
We're here today to let you know that the police and the fbi are working tirelessly on this case.
今天我们要告诉大家 警方和FBI正在竭尽全力破案
We'd like to stress to the women who work on these streets to please take caution.
我们要强调的是 在这些街道工作的女性请特别小心
All right, first I'm gonna give a brief description of the man we're looking for, and then we'll take some questions.
好的 我先对要找寻的这个男人 做个简要描述 然后接受提问
We believe the man responsible for these crimes works on or around capitol hill,
我们确信犯案男子在国会山附近工作
possibly at a research or advocacy group dealing with issues of crime control or prevention.
可能是致力于罪案控制或预防的研究或倡导小组
The lower the group is on the washington food chain, the better.
在华盛顿食物链中 该小组所处位置越低越有可能
This guy, he feels like his voice isn't being heard, and make sure to check for any advocacy groups promoting morality or values.
此人觉得自己的呼声不被重视 确保查找所有倡导道德观和价值观的小组
Ok, reality check.
好的 事实监测
What you're looking for--needle.
你就是在
This--haystack.
大海捞针
Garcia, we don't have to find it.
Garcia 无需找到它
We just need to get to the people who can.
只是要让找得到的人看
Ok.
好的
You could've done that much more quietly.
你完全可以悄悄进行
I know.
我知道
There's some people I'd like for you to meet.
我想让你见一些人
Right this way.
这边请
Just what point are you trying to make?
你究竟想说明什么?
These women described similar experiences with the same man.
这些女人描述了跟同一个男人的类似经历
We showed them police mug photos, and they didn't recognize him.
但没有在警方存档的照片中认出此人
We thought maybe you might know who he is.
我们想或许你认识他
Did you think you could shock me by treating me to this sideshow?
你认为用这种杂耍表演 就能吓倒我吗?
Sideshow?
杂耍?
Lady, enough of the men you work with treat themselves to us every day.
女士 跟你工作的男人中 多的是自动送上门找乐子的
My apologies, ladies.
我道歉 女士们
Could you please tell the congresswoman who it is we're looking for.
能否请你们告诉女议员 我们找的到底是什么人?
He's tall and bald, and he's got sad eyes.
他高个 秃顶 眼神悲伤
He was always wearing a turtleneck with this long, dark coat, looked like a morticiaN.
习惯穿套领毛衣外加深色长外套 看上去象殡仪业者
That's right.
没错
Hung around just watching for months before he finally got his nerve on, but then he just wanted to watch.
徘徊数月进行观察 待好不容易有了兴致 他想做的也只是看看而已
Freak paid me and racine 200 bucks to turn each other's knobs,
那个怪人付了200元 让我和Racine
but then he started screaming at us that we were low women.
但随后大叫我们是低贱的女人
Same thing with me, and his voice got real high and nasal when he got excited.
我也是 他兴奋的时候声音非常刺耳 鼻音很重
Does that sound like anyone that you know?
听起来熟悉吗?
No.
不
I'm gonna read you a list of groups that lobbied on behalf of your legislation.
我来念一份为你的法案 进行各方面疏通的小组名单
Keeping in mind the description you just heard,
记住刚才听到的描述
tell me if anyone associated with these groups could be the man we're looking for.
告诉我这些小组中是否有我们要找的人
Uh, "the crime policy institute, "the center for safety,
呃 "犯罪政策团队" 安全中心
citizens' brigade, decency watch
市民自卫队 正当监视小组
oh, my god.
哦 我的上帝
Decency watch?
正当监视小组?
The man who runs it.
那个负责人
Ronald weems.
Ronald Weems
Do you know him?
你认识他?
No.
不
I mean, yes, but he's a nobody.
我是说 是的 但他是个小角色
But he fits this description?
可是符合描述?
Perfectly.
非常匹配
I need to get back to work.
我要回去工作了
Again?
又要回去?
Yes, again.
是的
Can't be helped.
必须如此
We're looking for ronald weems.
我们要找Ronald Weems
I-I'm sorry.
抱歉
You just missed him.
你们刚好错过
Why don't you come back in a couple hours?
不如几小时后再来?
Don't you wanna know why we're here?
不想知道我们为什么来这儿吗?
Of course.
当然想
Yes.I'm sorry.
是的 抱歉
We're investigating the murders of local prostitutes.
我们在调查针对本地妓女的谋杀案
I-I'm glad that ronald is helping you with that, but I'm afraid I don't know anything about it.
很高兴Ronald对你们有所帮助 但我对此恐怕一无所知
We'd just like to take a look in your husband's office.
我们只想看看你丈夫的办公室
Please?
可以吗?
Ronald doesn't allow anyone in there.
Ronald不让任何人进去
I'm sorry.
对不起
You really should come back.
你们最好过会儿再来
In the last 6 months did your husband start asking you to play out sexual fantasies?
过去六个月 你丈夫是否 开始要求你进行各种性幻想?
Excuse me?
什么?
Possibly even berated you if you played along?
你如果合作 可能还会斥责你?
I don't think that's appropriate.
我觉得这种谈话不合适
When it finally stopped about a month ago, you were relieved.
一个月前中止时 你感到如释重负
Ma'am, you're afraid to ask us why we're here.
女士 你不敢询问我们为什么来
Now, in your heart, you know we're not here because ronald's helping us with this investigation.
因为你心里已经知道 这并非因为Ronald有助我们调查
Good night.
晚安
You've been glad to have him leave the house at odd hours, because he's been angry and frustrated.
因为他持续气愤失落 你宁可让他在这种奇怪的时刻离家
When he comes home, he feels like the man you married again.
当他回来时 感觉上还是当初嫁的男人
His office.
他的办公室
Please.
拜托
"Why won't they clean them off the street?
为什么不将她们从街上清除?
"The blood is on their hands.
她们的手上沾满鲜血
"I see a world set free of vice and vermin, cleansed of the blood of the whores who walk the street.
我看到一个没有罪恶和歹徒的世界 是用路上妓女的鲜血洗刷干净的
"Do you know where your husband went?
知道你丈夫去哪儿了吗?
He said he had work to do.
他说要去工作
hey, you ever seen this guy, huh, out here doing business?
嘿 见过这个人 呃 来这儿玩吗?
Can you tell me if you've seen this man?
能否告诉我你们有没有见过这人?
Ma'am, you ever seen this face?
女士 见过这个人吗?
No?
没有?
Never? Out here talking to the ladies?
从来没有吗? 跟这的女士说话的也没有吗?
Sorry.
对不起
You seen this guy?
见过这个家伙吗?
You sure?
确定?
I ain't seen him.
没见过
Thank you.
谢谢
My man, you ever seen this cat out here doing business?
兄弟 见过这家伙来这玩吗?
Excuse me.
打扰
You ever seen this man before?
以前见过这个男人吗?
Nothing?
一无所获吗?
No. You?
是的 你呢?
Seen him?
见过他吗?
You didn't even look.
你都没看
Do you know this man?
-认识这个人吗? -不认识
Thank you.
谢谢
He's gotta be out here somewhere.
他一定就在这附近
How much?
多少钱?
Hey, where you going?
嘿 去哪儿?
Don't run away from me.
别跑
Ronald weems, don't move!
Ronald Weems 不许动!
Put your hands in the air and get down on your knees.
举起双手 跪下
They lied to me.
他们骗我
Get her out of here!
带她离开!
On the ground!
跪下!
He killed my friend!
他杀了我朋友!
I know. Stop it!
我知道 停下!
She maced me.
她对我用了催泪瓦斯
Yeah, she did.
对 是的
They said they'd clean 'em off the streets.
他们说会把她们从街上清除
They lied.
他们撒谎
What was I supposed to do?!
那我又能怎么办?!
Hey.
嘿
Hi.
嗨
I heard the juvenile authorities let you go today.
听说少教所今天会将你释放
I'm sorry I wasn't there.
抱歉我没去
Mm, it's all right.
没关系
Where's your mom?
你妈妈在哪儿?
Oh, she had to go back to work.
哦 她必须回去工作了
I told her I was coming to see you.
我告诉她我来见你
So were you there when they caught him?
那么抓住他的时候 你在那儿吗?
Yeah, I was.
对 我在
Did he say how long he knew what he was?
他说了是多久前认清自己的吗?
No.
没有
Well, do you think it's possible to maybe talk to him or
你觉得我能不能跟他谈谈或者...
I'm sorry.You're not him.
抱歉 你不是他
Who we are is--it's constantly evolving.
我们是谁--这是不断变化的问题
I'm a lot older than you, and I'm changing all the time.
我比你大很多 每时每刻都在改变
You know, this-- this job changes me.
你知道吗 这个--这个工作改变了我
You've changed me.
你改变了我
You sought me out to try to understand how not to harm people.
是你让我思考和明白如何 才能不对人们构成伤害
It's a far more important part of who you are than the one that scares you.
比起让你害怕的那部分 这部分的你要重要得多
My mom wants to have me go to a hospital for a little bit.
我妈妈想让我上医院住一段时间
Maybe that's not such a bad idea.
这主意或许不坏
You know, once they lock me up, they're never gonna let me out of there.
知道吗 一旦被锁起来 他们决不会放我出来了
You don't know that.
你并不知道
Whatever.
无所谓啦
I just came to say good-bye.
我只是来告别
When you going in?
什么时候去?
Supposed to be tomorrow.
明天
So, last night of freedom.
那么 自由的最后一夜
I don't know.
不知道
I'm-- thank you for caring.
我--谢谢关心
T.S. Eliot wrote between the desire and the spasm, ""between the potency and the existence,"
T.S. Eliot写到 “在渴欲与痉挛之间 在潜在与存在之间”
between the essence and the descent, falls the shadow.
“在本质和传承之间  幕帘重重”
This is the way the world ends.
“这就是世界中止的方式”
"You looking for a date?
找人陪吗?
Suit yourselF.
随你吧
You scared me.
你吓死我了
I'm actually looking for a date.
我想找个人陪
Come on.
来吧
Come on, you and me, we're hitting the town.
来吧 你和我 游遍整个镇
No offense, garcia, but I'm not really feeling like I'd make the, uh, best company right now.
恕我直言 Garcia 但我确实觉得 现在当不了最佳玩伴
Oh, no.
哦 别
Up.
起来
Do not make me hurt you.
别逼我伤害你
There you go.
就这样
Just relax.
放松一点
Don't you wanna feel me?
不想摸我吗?
See?
来?
There.
这儿
How does that make you feel?
你觉得这样如何?
I don't know.
不知道
Yes, you do.
不 你知道
It's-- it's not right.
这--这不对
It's ok, baby.
没关系 宝贝
You're just nervous.
你只是有点紧张
There you go.
就是这样
It's not working.
没用
Everything's gonna work just fine.
一切都会好起来的
Don't laugh at me.
别笑我
Nobody's laughing.
没人在笑
Let me help you.
我来帮你
Don't touch me.
别碰我
You're just a whore.
你只是个妓女
You have no idea what I could do to you!
你根本不知道我会对你做什么!
How 'bout we both just walk away?
不如就此分开?
No charge.
不用付钱
No.
不
You don't wanna do this.
你不能这样做
I have to.
必须如此
Have you met esther?
见过Esther吗?
You like?
喜欢吗?
Only 150,000 miles on her.
只开过十五万英里
Hello.
你好
Hey.
嗨
What?
什么?
Oh, god.
哦 上帝
Uh, uh, stay-- stay where you are.
呃 呃 呆在-- 留在原地
I'm calling an ambulance.
叫救护车
I--I need you to drive, garcia.
开车 Garcia
Yeah, yeah.
好
He just started slashing himself up.
他拼命地砍自己
Oh, dear lord.
哦 我的上帝
All right, give me your scarf.
好吧 把你的围巾给我
Tie it around there as tight as you can.
尽量绑紧这里
Get--get anything at all, a belt.
用--随便用什么 带子
Tie it!
绑住!
Is it tight?
紧吗?
I think so.
我想可以
The paramedics stop.
急救人员到了
Don'T.
别
I'm gonna keep pressure on him.
我要一直压着他
Where the hell are the medics?!
急救人员到底在哪里?!
I don't know.
我不知道
Is it tight?
够紧吗?
I don't know. I think so.
不知道 我想可以
Don'T.
别
I'm not gonna let you die.
我不会让你死的
No.
不
Where are the medics?
急救人员呢?
You can let go now.
你现在可以放手了
Sir.
先生
Reid.
Reid
Sir, we're paramedicS.
先生 我们是急救队员
We're here to help you.
我们来帮你
Can you tell me your name, sir?
能告诉我你的名字吗 先生?
How did she know to call reid?
她怎么知道要通知Reid?
Nathan set reid's business card on the table before he cut himself, like a suicide note.
Nathan割自己之前把Reid的名片 放在桌上 有点象遗书
Paramedics say he wouldn't've made it without you.
急救队员说 幸亏有你在 他才能活下来
You saved his life.
你救了他一命
He wanted me to let him die.
他希望我让他死
He's sick.
他有病
He needed saving.
需要救助
How many people's lives did I risk in the future?
将来我还要经历多少这样的生命危险?
Profiles can be wrong.
档案可能会出错
What if it's not?
如果没有呢?
What if next time, he kills somebody?
如果下一次 他杀了人呢?
Then you catch him.
那时你再抓住他